<resources>
    <string name="app_name">NaijaHealthCentre</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="name">name</string>
    <string name="lga">lga</string>
    <string name="whatsebola">WHAT IS EBOLA ?</string>

    <string name="meaningebola"> The Ebola virus causes an acute, serious illness which is often fatal if untreated. Ebola virus disease (EVD) first appeared in 1976 in 2 simultaneous outbreaks, one in what is now, Nzara, South Sudan, and the other in Yambuku,
Democratic Republic of Congo.
The latter occurred in a village near the
Ebola River, from which the disease takes its name.</string>
    <string name="transmission">TRANSMISSION</string>
    <string name="transmissiondef">It is thought that fruit bats of the Pteropodidae family are natural Ebola virus hosts.  Ebola is introduced into the human population through close contact with the blood,  secretions, organs or other bodily fluids of infected animals such as chimpanzees, gorillas, fruit bats,   monkeys, forest antelope and porcupines found ill or dead or in the rainforest.  Ebola then spreads through human-to-human transmission via direct contact (through broken skin or mucous membranes)  with the blood, secretions, organs or other bodily fluids of infected people, and with surfaces and materials  (e.g. bedding, clothing) contaminated with these fluids.  Health-care workers have frequently been infected while treating patients with suspected or confirmed EVD.  This has occurred through close contact with patients when infection control precautions are not strictly practiced.  Burial ceremonies in which mourners have direct contact with the body of the deceased person can also play  a role in the transmission of Ebola.  People remain infectious as long as their blood contains the virus.</string>
    <string name="treatment">TREATMENT AND VACCINE</string>
    <string name="treatmentdef">Supportive care-rehydration with oral or intravenous fluids- and treatment of specific symptoms,  improves survival. There is as yet no proven treatment available for EVD. However,   a range of potential treatments including blood products, immune therapies and drug therapies are currently being evaluated.  No licensed vaccines are available yet, but 2 potential vaccines are undergoing human safety testing.</string>
    <string name="prevention">PREVENTION AND CONTROL</string>
    <string name="preventiondef">Good outbreak control relies on applying a package of interventions, namely case management,  surveillance and contact tracing, a good laboratory service, safe burials and social mobilisation.  Community engagement is key to successfully controlling outbreaks. Raising awareness of risk factors for  Ebola infection and protective measures that individuals can take is an effective way to reduce human transmission.  Risk reduction messaging should focus on several factors:  Reducing the risk of wildlife-to-human transmission from contact with infected fruit bats or monkeys/apes and  the consumption of their raw meat. Animals should be handled with gloves and other appropriate protective clothing.  Animal products (blood and meat) should be thoroughly cooked before consumption. Reducing the risk of human-to-human transmission from direct or close contact with people with Ebola symptoms,  particularly with their bodily fluids. Gloves and appropriate personal protective equipment should be worn when   taking care of ill patients at home. Regular hand washing is required after visiting patients in hospital,   as well as after taking care of patients at home.</string>
    <string name="who">WHO RESPONSE</string>
    <string name="whodef">WHO aims to prevent Ebola outbreaks by maintaining surveillance for Ebola virus disease and  supporting at-risk countries to developed preparedness plans. The document provides overall  guidance for control of Ebola and Marburg virus outbreaks</string>
</resources>
